if you can deal with in today's class
you'll be able to conquer fatigue
proposal
and you can take over the world
or at least
read resigned and said read
hurtful ticket
he commanded
email submission
year
seven try to figure out are
how exactly is designed to work to
report demands
but it's not copying too that the portal
gothic you'll see me ticket you go back
into the real but yours
or you hear me trying to pay for it
doesn't work
uh... sort of control y
so matter why twenty pasted
if you don't do anything else we have
met a wide olfactory previous support
and trees
with the same as
patron cal menu
go back to me differently
items takes them in
takes the last one
it's going to start with but you're
twenty one
so to make sure
that you have gone through
be make directory
dash p formal rectory still the slash
plot for someone
cd interact directly re
and to double check you can do p dvd
to see where you're at
and then
you can do it that you get out this file
if you want to be copying and pasting
all about it today
and doing it dot
an easy way to get that your elicited
from the higher teaching or you can
right-click
on or filed copyright protection
we're gonna talk about person binary
data
i picked this table file thanks to plan
a race
who suggested using assets which is a
format
that i have to look at the definition of
its a smooth pressed estimate trajectory
from the apart pos pac
inertial navigation systems
and that i think about
b_f_ that format is that it's very
uniform and simple
it's not
a great example in terms of complexity
when we start off with only one jump
into the motivating formats like
theories on
or dec right konsberg formats which have
all kinds of different restructures
and lots of different
groups of data and it was really much
more complex to parse
but if you get the basics of
the next class or see you as we work
through
pursing primary care
this'll give you the tools that you can
go and work
on those file format will be able to
parse diamond and read them on your own
and while that's not useful in terms of
promising big survey data you know when
you package like n_b_c_'s tumour
hi pack or carrots to read through goes
in with your for processing
when things go wrong we want to build
towards the handle what you want these
datasets
if he could build say some reports there
are mac degenerated
dig into plugs and questions about how
things are actually working
being able to parse that binary d_a_'s
super powerful
and it changes your view of how mostly
being and other data systems work when
you can actually get in there and see
what the vendors really doing
doubt of your two roles that when you
start out there something goes wrong
north different than you expect might be
able to figure it out
jonathan dot o_ n_
who's here also teaches a
both in person class he's taught one so
far
hopefully if you are seeing this stuff
you going to work with him you have a
better chance of focusing more on
the more the demand last on the
mechanics of writing code to parse that
fire data
if you're trying to learn programming as
he's work with more to be in data it's
going to be a bit challenging
that's definitely doable but it's just
extra work so being able to focus more
on
the complexities of arson red prospered
in a format has plenty of work on its
own
so let me show you
a quick
tour of the format we're going to be
getting into
so you see at least once
i've got a link in here to the full pos
pac quickstart guide if you want to read
more about it you could do that on their
own if you get interested in this
but given your table up there in the
notes and i've just written the
pearson's
and this format consists of seventeen
parameters
per message that comes back from the
system
and they're all doubles we've
think about
that we'll talk a little bit more about
their types
here but they're all the same type which
makes life will be easier for us in
terms of how the data stored
and we've got time
when that message was generated
we've got latitude more student
are altitude are velocities roll pitch
heading
our tele rations annex wines the
and our angular acceleration connects
wines the we're going to focus just on
these top guys appear are time lodging
wants to help the
but we need to be able to skip past all
of those guys who read about your
records
and in the file with an aspect
basically with we're seeing terms
datafile missus position zero
each records the position
seventeen
this will start ah... that's the first
record
second record
and so forth
if you can read through each of these
blocks each one of these contains this
data
as appointed by its these are
eight bytes each
and so it's eight
times seventeen bites long for each one
of these groups
soul be reading chunks of vote to go
along
you're going to be able to parse the
part two of those that you want
and be able to return
they ship tracks
it shows which it's going and when the
ship was at that particular location
and the using i've been out for weather
deposit act software returns a very high
rate
i'm not sure how many hurts it is
but it was basically many millions of
records i'd estimate that down to just a
few so i think we have a common records
and or sample file
and that makes it a lot easier work with
because the original files when you get
from are several hundred megabytes or
more in here and working with about
twenty k
bites filesize
had just taken every and records
i took this record skip the whole bunch
and that no one down the list
and cases out into a file
dot pasting pasting but actually using
code to do it
to just break those records and bills
you something that shows the whole
subtract the decimated down to just a
few points
so let's
jump into some binary data
just about that table
i have a commands
keys curl to grab that data file
from at a pace that n
days
protects them there is no check
something anywhere in the file thousand
checks on that iran
so this file has no information about
how many records are or any validation
of them
it could be corrupted
and the only way you might guess that
is if you have been outside checked some
or if it didn't white if you had
you got to be and and you have a half
record or something like that
would mean that maybe something like
that
junked or something like that this is
not the most robust
format on the planet
you want to send it over and reliable
network connection because you're gonna
have troubles copy
and before i forget
them taking this class of his pieces out
of something i reply fear in preparation
for its so i put a link appear undersea
also
a predominant thirty pages
uh... lots of detail with paragraph
describing things it's not
fully bake their step away some working
to get done in terms of the polish taxed
but for this class there's a lot more
information and background at that link
for the wealthy here
hale described everything and politely
but most of a good detail
thank you you uh... a lot more
background read
so hopefully that'll help with this it
more difficult topic
so now we've got the file
so it starts off with twenty cheap k
tend to be unzip it
sample that's that
and we'll see how that we have it
so the confession here but being a such
a tiny fire they went from twenty to you
four seven three
twenty-two
seven
twenties who meet the press in this file
didn't really help us too much here
but it's a small doesn't really matter
and let's take a quick peek into
the data
before we had a pipe bomb will try some
other tools to look at this
so the first one i love doing and kept
clear just hide stuff
his always run file on things
sophie safe i'll start a aspect
he comes back with a very informative
data
not very exciting
printed navarra
the next thing we can do is a command
called odi oracle plump
manoji
so it does
files an awful format
based turn is our normal
number scheme facie is octal may sixteen
is facts
if you start doing a lot of stuff with
computers joe and epstein is a fair bit
i don't expect you to pre-op tour hats
too much in this class
or if you can really understand but
we've got a little bit of octal a little
bit of tax you have a really troubling
noticed that were doing it
but this command will help dump stuff
and we can see what the binary might
look like
so we can do you
edit copy
toothpaste in
are cody
dash amy
staple but aspect but that they hadn't
to enter
and we have nothing above terribly
helpful
we continue our what's on this fire
sample thought aspect
hit answer
it says
this may be binary
sure when i will take a look
and unlike
some of our other formats they got lucky
there were some tax hiding in there
if we look at this is all binary data
there's nothing here that gives us a
whole lot of hands to stop
this is just to show you that
don't be afraid of looking at binary
data if you go on the stand it
all well and you know we don't get this
doesn't
make sense to human just staring at the
screen
we give it a go and see what happens
today queue to get out of laughs
this is sort of how it works when i look
at new data files that i'm not used to i
get a lot of stuff with poor or no
documentation or i don't even know what
the format type is just hear the files
contained in it
these are the strategies i tend to use
when looking at data
and just keep trying them until you get
some in the first making sense
we can try
a different cody
octal dumped it's actually possible to
specify
the type in the reasons we know these
are doubles
we can tell it that we've got a bunch of
doubles and maybe give it a shot and see
what happens
and i'm gonna give you a simple or file
that i know what that what's in there i
just wrote a file with binary in same
format that just has the numbers one
through i think sixteen or seventeen
seeking grab this
debbie get command
the gravel sample file
off the web server
and if color s one dob and it's not
really any particular
suppressive fire last one dot then
we can get data
ice one dot then we do now lots of it
and we see that is just a little tiny
hunterdon thirty six
bite file
telstra oracle tom
and lost eight dash tea for tight
floating-point
and w every demand page if you want to
see you
how to specify all the stuff and give it
a shot
test one top ten
we hit enter
aforesaid association isn't the most fun
but this is here
power ten exponents we have zero
three four five all the way down to
now answers and plus one down here since
eleven twelve thirteen fourteen fifteen
sixteen
so it shows that we can
look at my married it wasn't tools are
not necessarily the most fun
if you want to work with data
the storm
is mostly just an inspection thing to
sort of people look into data
if you don't see anything here that
makes a lot of sense they just move on
and don't worry about it but sometimes
it does give you insight into what you
look at it
at that point
i think it's time to move on the python
because it's much more interesting to
look at the inside a pipeline
that command-line tools
hard so much fun
i pay phone
can remember the log starved for lost
time as well
go ahead and do you along star
but we've logged everything in there
fmd log start
dash code dash r
form dash class dash twenty one dot pipe
i'm leaving out the dash t this time
the timestamps
it was worth trying if you think you
need time stands for what you're working
on
say you're actually working with the
real time system talking to a life sonar
time just like you really important when
you go back and look at your notes
here that is generating extra melissa
hit enter
and if you want to see
what do you want to make sure it's
working
and i'd mistyped class
what obviously did so hopefully you can
type class correctly
and all this a pain
and you'll see the remarks certainty
written
what's going to import the models organi
news today
school say import struct structures the
python module that reads
binary data of all sorts of different
types
imports numbed by it
umpires a great way working with the in
terms of big arrays
some data formats that will work with
can work in num potted some can't
destruct one is so simple and it's so
uniform that creating an array of this
is not a bad idea so we can
contribute that
n_f_l_ link here
pressure off looking at struct someone
and then click this link
firefox herewith
documentation
in here this table
is a table character codes that you can
you tell right on
what a good day to you got
now some of you may not have ever worked
with
this level of data in terms of through
more computer science the view of what's
behind the scenes
but we do it binary data doing with its
invites
when you have a chunk of memories in
your computer
if you've got eight bytes
which is sort of typical size of data is
anywhere between
one bite and he fights
so if you have a character
every one of these guys gonna represent
one character
and that will be your
see up there are left in the format
codes
then you can have this fifo one bite
number which can go from here if you
could def by the fifth unsigned to
doesn't have a plus or minus if it sign
it goes from minus one twenty seventh of
course
went from seven twenty-six
and then you can start having
various sizes that go
in california too
or four
or eight
bites on memory so
in order to have a double floating point
number
it's going to use all eight of those
bites
a regular floating point number which is
four
the more bites you get the more
range of numbers you can represent
with this evening specify what kind do
you have
and it takes a little while to get used
to working with
numbers on this level
as what you see this table so that you
know it's there in case
you start working with data down the
road it's got lots of different types if
you work with us around
cars performer for example
you end up using
hahaha those character coat that there
when you try to read a different types
of daylight at the clock packet
and they've got
uh... mid water column data and
cd capital crimes the fact that it's all
store differently
and you'll need to use those cuts we are
cover them with a simple our world today
d for double
nabi are
floating-point eight-by-ten number
you may run into terms like indian this
which means
computers can represent things
with different supporters of those bites
for today don't worry trendiness it's
all going to be the same so we don't
have to worry about that
in the long run you can get bit pretty
badly by
when you're doing is bigger little
indian
where was written and where you're
reading it
but for today
were working with the same day to the
same andean miss on
the computer here
and where it was written so they can
just not worry about that
for you for the founder of the term
and if you go stand couple hours
gurgling and reading up on andy nethin
still probably a little confused
so i have a bunch of examples and hear
of writing out data
and i don't want you to worry too much
about this but just copy this block
this is not the best way to write pipe
bombs but it's really compact
if we just take those in there
it's gonna write a whole bunch of files
it might be
i did not import math
i had one where a m
i rode out
the number pie
fifteen air
i hadn't done import math pipe
to get by on the air
what i've done here is right about your
file so if we can do you tell us that
show
we have a bunch of small sample files
without being on the end
of various different sorts and i'd use
the letter code
lower case p capital being one dot
typically give you a hint if the letter
code that's trucked uses
for what's in there
let's take a quick look at one of those
so i think we'll take a look at it
this one b dash series dot then
and i've used destruct pack
to write the data
we're not gonna worry so much about
writing and it's going to have some
examples in is that right out the data
mcallen too much stuff
but if we hope in up to current
directory
control x control af
uh... period
i had open before some ahead g here
interac notary fresh
and we have a whole bunch of files
so hopefully you got
or range of file showing up in your
directory so control expert relapse
and then carry it if it shows up until
the slash class point one
controllers controller period and press
enter
hit g in there to make sure it's up to
date
you can hear by stimson whenever you
feel like
and there is a capital b dash series dot
pinne
enter
it turned out when you write numbers in
random binary data it can sometimes look
like strings
so i brought us a sequence of numbers
i'm gonna show you one quick moti max
that
i don't expect you to understand what
you see but elise have heard of this one
q cynthia meta acts
dash mullen and in the file b dash
series dot then
as this switch to a binary viewing mode
to hit after
and it's going to show you
the hex characters on the left
and if you look at the right there's a
matching
highlighting character of the there
this is very confusing when you first
see it
and maybe the first
tanner are trying to see it
so just sort of
get a feel for it
if you are on
give control x two
to split your window
any type medic acts
and they end and then press enter
amarin thai pass key
a_t_f_'s seat i'd
enter
and we're now brought up
the unix manual page
for the ascii character codes
and if we scroll down a little bit
we have
octal
dot samal which is our basic and affirm
or when you count
and hacks numbers
and then what that character tends to
mean
are written down here and so you can
look up
if we have seventy three
people i love it
seventy three in terms of uh...
hex number
we can scroll down so we hit seventy
three which is right here
having knock-on fifty carefully acta on
how difficult it is to follow many pages
of ascii
and match them up here
but if you work jericho there you know i
think that's equally here
so this
seventy-three right here
that character coaches p_m_s_ and we
have a last look better
uh... they're just had a copy of peace
for now
and if you come back later on hopefully
they'll make a little more sense by the
end class
that block of code
which is to write some files
so sometimes alex but you just copy and
paste code it'll do some stuff and then
we'll work through
how it actually works
slowly in the class
so it's the topic with a lot of things
going on and it sort of a chicken in the
egg
and we can spend
few months going through this and try
you know the details and then you might
have a really good sense of it but we're
gonna do the
i hope you get
of just of what's going on
and you don't feel too overwhelmed but
if you're not getting everything that
we're doing here it's okay
this is more the exposure load
of just having seen a least wants so
that when you get to it have to work
right here for a little bit more
familiar with uh... topic
eating
it's hard to ignore the column as a
member so i have to go back up to the
top
i could be smarter i could you control x
two win there
and then this would have been the wife
induces search seventy-three control
hats
so there is in the best mccollum
and there it's in the house opt-out that
would be a much better way i'm in mode
where you say
matter
acts
hetzel h_e_ expelled
dash mode
and this is the programmer hacker moda
looking into
went ahead and quickly max
will discuss acquits turnover
yells this figure
so for that max and you can't relax
controller
ceases to control its one so now if you
control act controller yep an outside
class
slash twenty one
press answer
case in either in their here in the
right directory
so now you can hit enter on the twenty
one tight on binary files that were so
click on that tonight after work while
pino replace
i think you might have awful com turner
here's a quick on that one
and i think you have told suggested that
i had open
them and page and i splitting with the
control act for you
that's was the window act of done before
and then i scrolled part of it to work
to see the header with this op told us
for hacks
and i scroll to bottom part of the
control at searching for the number of
looking for
with respect for spring time in their
family is your kind of desperate
and you're struggling pretty hard with a
format we have some troubles this is
like that
i'm having a bad day i need to run this
morning
at that point probably going to be
reading the manuals internal audit a
little bit more era
but we can see it
comeback in your memory that day to your
stock sitting someplace with the day
that you need to work on
all right so i'm gonna go back
too
are org file
let's go ahead and just jump linda
aspect final
we've got those other files their anna
if you've ever feeling uncomfortable or
you're feeling like maybe you've got
some more nuanced writing different
kinds of files
those files are now sitting in your
virtual machine free to play with down
the road
and you can open them up in the max you
can run other plans on them
and try them from within python as you
see fit
but let's go ahead and open up our
sample aspect file
so if we say ask
s bt underscore file
equals open
sample and then attitude essay pressed
count
and that will open the file
doesn't know anything about it
um... if you're on windows always forget
this
primary just now
you can't just open a binary file on
when does it seems to be kind of broken
with reading files
so you have to print because dua bhi
if you're mode
so we have here on the windows trying to
do this
come ask me
when you end up doing in your profile
that's not going to work to open buyer
did directly on windows personal
recently
opening and reading files
but now we can do is because they asked
that
data equals
aspect
file dot read
we're just gonna grab everything in that
file because not to biggest twenty two k
amber a dump it into
very ball and see what happens here we
get
ticket counter
it's as if dole that data quickly into
uh... memory now if you're reading a
real estate file that's a seven hundred
megabytes this three command might take
you a few years
later on we'll talk about how to
zoom through the file bit by that
and now we can tycoons to see we've
gotten our space
that looks pretty gross
blackwell weird question marks inside of
a bubble hand squares in zero zero ss
it basically was intuit for our strength
for us
but it's not really characters
so we really have to work with it and
use this truck command try interpret
that as something useful
now if we stay tight
s that data
should match up exactly but we got there
that it's a nasty are
you can say wife
of our ask that data
and should be the same life is our file
so we had twenty two thousand seven
hundred and twelve bytes
enacting a blog
where jumps right into
this command called struct unpack that
actually untaxed binary data
so i'm gonna try to make a mistake first
to show you what it looks like before we
do it right
hinging on the notes i have a just right
so will say
struct
dot unpacked
everything to help with the question
mark
this help isn't the most helpful
unpacked a string containing taxi
structured data
you don't know what that means self
that's less than helpful thanks guys
deficit unpack
dash d
for our double from that table that we
had on the web
and i am a profit are
aspect
now please pass the whole
time block of data
it's looking for one double
and i found twenty two you've set the
eight
bites they found twenty two thousand
something or other bites
and said i don't really
like that
so we need to do is slice off the first
eight fights
presenter
and we get back some number
it's cartel that number of right or
wrong
so what slowed up
one of our data files we've got and
we'll try to same thing
with something that we know what it
might be
tell us so we've got a few files a try
i've written this one here
d dash series dot then works for a
series of numbers further
ha stepping up
so we can say it is
datafile equals open
d dash series dot
and data equals
the underscore file
dot read
wife of data so we just got eighty
fights in there
and we can say
struct
unpack
d for a double
and then that we want to pass it in
and just those first he fights
and we get back the number is zero point
zero actually wrote zero
one-two-three-four
and this file
so it's actually pretty nice
that we actually can prove to ourselves
as always good to start but they did it
you know andrea dot before you go in
trying to bring something where
we don't know
our first time number in this aspect
final
i don't know have any sense of what that
number is going to be
so how do we know if we got it right or
wrong it could be kinda hard to
understand
so that's given as a result proof that
we can read some binary data
what we can do
is if we've got multiple bites are
groups of things we want to read
we can specify more pple letters in the
strength of the type of things going on
pac
who can say struct
dot unpacked
and influence you
two doubles
and the can say data
colin
command is the map in here eight
times to you
so sixteen
and hopeless opac that unpacked the
first two numbers with two deeds
so when i run package zero in one
we can also cut unpacked all of them
we can say
didi icp ten of them
there's five
six seven eight nine ten they got the
right number of them
and he had ten deans
you can't hack all ten of words in one
one command here
president make sure cut
because typing ten days is really
hard to do an error prone
you can write the number ten saying i
want pac ten of these
double floating-point numbers and their
prepress enter
family unpacked all time
so let's try those on our aspect
so back here
we can do strict on pac
didi and we can take
the second two numbers which should be
are allowed to and longitude
with the carousel this is the first
eight and then we've got
loudoun longitude
school say struct
unpack
didi
asked that
data
cohen twenty four
so that's the sixteen bytes long
presenter
and we get back to numbers that are
really
hard to read
and the reason that's hard to read
is that it's not in decimal to curries
its
radians around the earth
which is a little hard to think about it
for not used to it and i'm definitely
not used to it
so instead of going from zero to three
sixty degrees it goes from zero two two
five around here
in if you tell me how many radians we
are firm
prince mean i had no idea
you know where work some more negative
on our longitude in world of positive on
a lot of seed
but i have no idea what that number
between zero one
high-affinity
so let's try and packing those
to but will switch dot
dede will do to d
so we've got two of them
now there are two rating numbers that
don't make a lot of sense yet
or we can unpack the whole thing so
since this is seventeen
doubled numbers
will unpacked the whole thing
will say is that you do you will be
seventeen d
and rather than slicing out
two doubles work for the for the past
and all of that except for
wat to do seventeen
times
eight bytes per
and we have seventeen of them
press answer
we now have all those fields from the
first records we've gone in
later in the file rapid first block a
vote
unpacked all those as numbers
unfortunately the units on all these
numbers are such that nothing in there
is a intuitive
sore after work a little bit to get
towards that
so in the notes yet what about the same
thing
pretty horrible
with i thought
if you have to number say acts com a
wine
you can step in to you
minus one
and nine nine nine
you can do assignments
with this
with commas inbetween
the first variable here
it's their side of the first number
come on to me that wiser second verbal
dog at the second member
so what we can do is unpack
is like what's over here on the right in
if we had seventeen
variable names on the left
wicket down the side always valuables
into
variable number names so that we can
actually understand which ones which
would have to count all the time
so let's go ahead and try it out
so first
willis type expel more wise you can see
it and say to you
and you should see acts come alive
getting set to minus one and nine nine
nine
so let's try that with our seventeen
variable names this in the a lot of
typing and sorry
so time latitude in as they're called
lapd can be lazy
launch
altitude and assessor breeding because i
don't want type out the whole means in
the notes thus no fun
plot of a lawsuit easy velocity
or
heading
wonder
i wonder what wonder is
x excel
call yell for fun
twine
exo this is really miserable
the excel
pain
fly
this is where we think a lot of typos
since the how many of us started taking
accurately and i'll probably fail
z ang
he calls
struct
unpack
and since you already know about using
the uh...
the county rd
if you want type out seventeen keys
you're welcome to u but uh... i'm sure
i'll make a mistake solstice q seventeen
decency or you know that
and then come on
him and will pass in it's going to be
again our data
going from zero to the size of one block
so seventeen
wouldn't either
seventeen
colin seventeen
times
boldest
copy apple walk
sold to edit copy
this is why doing that this way is
really not fun
simply paste
well you know what
aspect and i think u
so i decided and we have an akita
variable running around
re-enter
since i don't like that they did very
well because up to that again anatoly
data and so are we still tell me that
there's no data from now behind
so now if we typed news
we should see
q much junk fit on one screen
social if you're here
you'll see
auger both by name
and they've been stored into art
workspace
and you could then work with a
particular packet
tickets the job done
but better yet
what we can do the trick
that we can take
we can take
two different lists one a list of the
field names and then your list is a list
of allies who want to put in
and has this weird thing called zip in
python
and i didn't know about that
for the first
fifteen years of programming in pipeline
when i discovered it
i kick myself for not having discover
this before because it's really amazing
zippel take you sequences
and blend them together
and then we can create dictionary out of
them so if we say
x
here's our first list x
and one
too
sticks them together not very exciting
but if we then add
hey we want to make this into a
dictionary
this very weird syntax
which i didn't
discover on my own
these two lists
and turn them into a dictionary
so here's our first list of x and y
and then our series of numbers
it'll make a dictionary this way
that's except this at the y setbacks is
that the one and why i said to you
so take this one matches up with that
and i imagine that the fact
so we do is go ballistic of our field
names
and we could tear that up
with what comes back from structural
list of all of our values
so that way every time we do it we can
just call is quick command and take all
those field values and stuff it together
with our
actual values
and
end up with a dictionary
there we have one item for our packet
uh... aspect
information
so let's give it a try
since i don't feel like typing i'm gonna
copy
this block here refiners field
listed copied
paste
simply type
names to see with dot
we just have elice or tubal say they
worked the same
of all of our names of our field how we
want to call them
and then if we want to get our values
we can type values
equals struct
dot unpacked
and we had seventeen doubles
aspect underscored data
colin and then
time seventeen
and they should unpack
the seventeen values into
this value variables which has values
we have all those
values that we don't currently know very
well yet but will wilford figure not
minutes
and now we can use for the weary dekhte
and then we can do is it
and those ipl se fields
names
values
and if i get enter
i now have a dictionary by name
that i can use
or if we're going to a simpler example
we can cut out for the first four of
each one
close to that
corn for
that's pretty huge
cohen four
soaring to grab the first four teach for
those put them together
and we create a very small dictionary
with our altitude latitude longitude in
time
so this feels pretty weird to me in
terms of being a python programmer
doesn't
they feel very natural
i keep this in my list of tricks
that i use and i sometimes after look it
up to remember how to do this
but this way
every time we've read one of these
aspect structures of seventeen bodies to
put in and you things binding because
using things by number trace me crazy if
i to river watson position fifteen
i'm never going to make it
yet to see yours
if you want to do anything else for the
but so far we're just playing around
but subdued factor that will save into
very well
so i'm gonna go back up to the one where
we didn't have the slicing
and mostly aspect
values
equals
and hit enter
so now we save you into
variables we can say type
aspect
values
presenter
and we have a dictionary
so it could be a lot easier to deal with
this dictionary by name so you start
working with things like a lot to want
to see if it makes sense
we convert it from releasing degrees
so if we do
import map i think that we did this
before but just to doublecheck import
map
map has
what i do a history and then you can see
reports that the highlight the commands
that we need to run so
so what we've done as we did the field
names equals with we copy dot gray at
the notes
so if you have that we have field names
and i would just copy and paste this out
of
the note if you can
and then what we didn't gays we said
values struct unpack
an elite unit seventeen p are expected
at we gave it the first
seventeen doubles
and then we save this very well aspect
values
people's that
field names values
so now what we're doing
since these guys are in radians
if any of you can think iranians
unimpressed
but we're gonna switch it to degrees
because i think most of us are much more
comfortable with the grease around here
there's a nice function inside of rap
artists use a map dot degrees you'll
take brians introverted platforms
and what we can then do is map dot
dei gene tab
and the question mark
you guys can read about math dot degrees
convert angle ex from reinstate agrees
that's one actually makes more sense
than most of the help
so we can save math dot
to corinn's
and we can say car aspect
values
and then we can say
so that's why don't you want to uh... to
longitude
we did miss tilly but then when we
copied and pasted great appear
you'll see that launches right now
it's one of those weird things is that
he's here or better to write allele in
g_ e_ r_ l_ and
and wanted to
after typing out all the time you go
crazy with writing out longitude
but if you're trying to
ricotta
in the long run
launches a little bit you here because
long unlocked
a little bit hard to notice the
difference
so hit enter
and work minus one forty six point six
seven so were
on the
western side of the united states
someplace
so what we can do that as we can add
that back into the dictionary
so we can then improve
what we've got to cut the raw dictionary
it was built from
one of these messages in the ass that
file so one record
and we can then interpret those
cumbersome so that makes more sense to
us and stuff the names that they carry
along side of what we had
so here
we can take the latitude that map of
degree who just didn't want to
and we can calculate those and stick
them inside that dictionary
so we can say
aspect
values
you say
launch degrees
equals
now doctor kary is
at that
values longitude
and was thinking for a lot of team
right over the place
routed to you
laboratories
his answer
with those two commands
we've now stored in that dictionary
more readable values
to go ahead and print out your aspect
values just type aspect underscore
values
presenter
and we have a short of a lot of things
so it's hard to find the ones who wants
but if you look here
latin degrees sixty degrees north
that implies that were up kind of in the
last area somewhere
that we look at the launch degrees work
minus one forty six point seven sore
definitely over in alaska
so this is working for the reading one
packet
became came back from our admission
ideation system
will begin to then is work on building a
system where we're going to go through
and read
mobile different version so we can
basically take to get out of this block
get backer dictionary
for the next one
previous one parts to do something with
it
and in the end of court review with this
series
it would like to be able to make a came
out map of where the ship was going to
end this particular
datafile
so we just want to have a priest track
from the aspect that says where to go
within the alaska
and what we need to start doing is
creating
basically an aspect module for ourselves
that will understand how to become a
teacher does
packet so we're gonna take this step it
will just done
try to turn into a file that we can
reuse
as you go along
so for some of you this actually gennady
practice dot if you go back now on ships
with the delivery plaques pos pac kind
of set up
you actually have these files coming out
of your molting system and you can then
do something like decimate this turn
into a priest track
and someone bumps you all watched these
files you can start building up crossing
system out of this kind of stuff
so let's go ahead and start into that
thurman's put the screen with control x
two
eminent open up a file
so if you're having trouble catching up
to where we are now everything that
we've done so far
you don't have to worry about you can
just
let go for now and come back to it
through the notes and take the time
similar open up
trolex control f
aspect dot pint
and if yet
white canvas the author of a somethin
let's start writing
a comment first
decoder
a plan x
pause pack
asked that
i am new
binary files
there's nothing like
in most of our lives or working out of c
a lot happens
and so it's really gets rough with
occupation because you get em is there
something and something critical happens
and yet the runoff from a comment
tata contention from beginning this kid
adults create a project called decode
and right now
we argue nothing other than
print hello from decoded
this is the most boring if
functions that does absolutely nothing
amber discover member however module
and call function from within our model
you see it before in this class
but he really doesn't hurt to do it a
few times
to get more comfortable with it
suffered u_n_ allies
overhear we should see hiding somewhere
in here
thought that it is
expect our client
family came to you
import
aspect
press enter
hopefully it just works
if you've got a typographic error
you might get uh... some sort of error
to take a peek at that
and see if you've got
common problems are
i_d_'s double quotes here dependable
quotes on both sides or the single
quotes
on
both sides
number of python single quotes a double
quotes work the same just have to have
the same
type on either side
and then we can save
aspects dot press time
and we'll see that we have a decodes any
known here
to review aspect decode
to print the season's at this back up to
folks in the back
answer
and it says hello from decode
that's not very exciting but we have a
function of interest are building up
to handle
processing one of these messages
so it started proving that
so here's the block we just did
before imports
amorous for improving this
if you are right
update it
preprint
seven times six
very important number
we have to
instead of just saying imports aspect
if we get in for aspect and we're ready
code again we don't get our update
we actually have to reload
aspect
press enter
and now three-run decode gency
hello from decode and the number forty
two
if you didn't see that the real world
you might not have saved remember that
you have to have
no stars in here
so that it tells you that the files
actually banned state to this
so we don't have it because that's very
much
we need to start working towards that
intersection getting ready to parse
awstats
let's create
um... main function double open up
our sample aspect file
breeding the data and get radar caller
decoding
so screening function of the doubt
domain
so thank you fred season a colin
enter it does the right hand and thing
for us
and look at them before
at the beginning and a functions is
often good to just have a print a story
in the function name
and then finishing her and the map
functioning so that
as you run the code bc each year
functions getting called it becomes
pretty obvious
will say starting
finishing
and in between
fools take it from our notes
so out those to you in
will say ask that
file equals open
sample thought aspect
am alerted with aspect
equals
asked that
files are read
my friends who are princy
saved that
i'm a big fan of
radio that echoed senior figure in
israel more code see if we can run it
some people are able to write the whole
thing first and then
start dividing that and i definitely
don't you go on that one
but he can pull it off
feel free to go four so read you are
reload again
reload
and then
now i could say aspect period
hit town
and now we have
are decode function
and i mean
function so it's call the main
press enter
and you see are
starting main finishing main
and nothing really happened
but we're getting closer
so let's see if we keep at it
a function that
will actually past that they tend to
decode
them will start doing something in that
deco so let's go ahead and call decode
but action for that bold check what
we've read and not be wise so print red
fights
so what we can do is to get the length
of our expected and make sure that it's
actually read
if this comes back to zero with might
have opened some other file
or pickets really large
you would never have helped in the right
thing for a spectator
that i'll print out the number plates
with bread
and then will call
decode
and will pass and decode are aspect data
now if we do it right now
are decode function doesn't take any
arguments
so it should be upset with us so stay
with control x control s
will do a reload
and then will rely on our main
and should be very unhappy
deco takes no arguments in the gate one
argument
so we're now having argument with decode
and houston jury english language which
is very ambiguous sometimes
feature improve
are decode function so we've got up here
uh... are improved decoding the notes so
let's get towards that
and the first thing to do is already in
some help
who'll say decipher
a aspect
datagram
binary
so that's our dock strength when we ask
for help from decoder foots gonna get
printed
and we're gonna add in here
gave insult takes some variable called
data
and now it's use that will say
colon
and the quote
common man lang data
let's say that
and so what should happen now is will
remain
will call this decoded
with are expected to listen to this
decode function
and should print out the same number of
bytes here that are uh... in our
right this minute bites
so let's get better shot
tools to a reloaded
andrew brown
and hopefully
you should see a twenty two seven one
two from the main
and our data length is twenty two seven
one two from inside of our fiction
if you gotta go off the ground if you
guys have any trouble for this because
we covered a lot of stuff to freeze
asking questions
and feel free to take a look at the join
or miss
document if you've got lots of free time
or having trouble sleeping you can end
up on the the python binary files dot
work file which goes into very much of
this and much greater detail
for example there's two pages before you
definition people what is the best that
truly it different talks a lot more
about what's going on
gives you much more detail
typically before
people teach
how do you do stuff they have a whole
classes on fixing bites and computer
organization architecture
we've skipped all that
and we said what does it go for it and
hope you guys get a feel for down the
road so
do you expect to be a little bit
confused
the number of flights and whatnot
and we'll get into that slowly but
surely
and by seeing some examples first when
you've read about it u r t i understand
and learn it much faster i think the
right now you'll feel a bit confused
don't worry about that
yeah i thought well convention and sorry
about how i i had
at a creditable whatever
which is more noise
so it's take a look at their so that
that's right that's what we did for
smooth this is what we did
now if you look at their
seeing on added stuff to my decode
function
nineteenth to go up to your decode often
and at a u_n_ fortunate and
singling out that cynthia
into the field
so if we start off
we added this near function with decoded
spectator
and then that we had to go improve this
guy to handle that so we added date
everything here is an argument
was their first step
i added a doc strength
not that important
that's why i did make that change and
that i added a print
data life
and annoying for the day here
isn't very or not being very exciting
but it should print out
the same thing here and here
globally investment in our department
okay
so what's the uh...
wind fourteen took over here and
satellite fourteen sold
free here
take a look at your code here and read
thus far into me
read out loud
wednesday
phillips's aspect underscore file equals
open simple but uh... and no one is the
here aspect of this profile people's
esta underscore foundry
and take a look at my end says expect
for our peoples and their clients and
asked that data
it's definite with walter reed outloud a
both cases
when you've read it your you'll catch
that state
you know there's lots of tricks
detecting in lots of tax
and so
everybody develop their own methods for
how to be more accurate
i like reading out loud it doesn't
always work for everybody but sometimes
i'm reading it up on the screen in
reading it on your screen between the
two your fought back
role court whenever you mistyped
that had a lot of those like three or
four will quote
and
cool stuff where it's hard to practice
on the aggregate images that have to
pass that data
intranet experts or
to take a look read the first one of my
decode
and that definition line and then read
yours so in the email window at the top
volpe narratives that decode reader
online alone
you don't have the so it's a function
call salute the name dana is local to
the function
sit here you're gonna pass in the past
but being a right there
and then in here is the call out
something to you that
confusing with the functions
when you have a function
whatever argument it is it means that
whenever it wants and it's gonna refer
to it by its own local name
friends
expected
are all we know it all away within half
of the year
and that's what sometimes confusing
thank you call that like food and flew
in above board
locally what everyone is all either
understanding how function works for you
could pass in
whatever anymore steve call
decode
yet so what we're going to you in the
next lecture is we're going to ask him
about the father and get rid of this
hard coded bombing here
women units that analytic command-line
and lying naked if we get time will make
it so that we can load up
you're going to and files
so i think what i can probably could
have won the pennant if i do that and we
couldn't see reading like three or four
s pets
and then uh... suspected examples but
i'm going to read to make this decreased
rectory twan separately on one one
though
so it's just i can't think we've covered
function so fast that people or
uncontrolled functions right now
so that's why i want to show another one
how people were quickly alot more
insisted
so arguing passing this is a little bit
tricky transit
of a concept